Ames Family Papers, 1812-2012
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. INDIVIDUALS
  - GENERATION III
    - GENERATION IV
      - Ames, Blanche Ames (1879-1969)
        - Activities
          - Art
            - Reproductive rights and women's health
              - New England Hospital
                - Correspondence
                - 1931-61, undated (Box 92, Folder 1-10)
                - Form letters, 1951-58, undated (Box 92, Folder 11)
                - Newsletters, 1933, 1953-54 (Box 92, Folder 12)
                - Clippings, 1953-55, undated (Box 92, Folder 13)
                - Pamphlets, 1953-54 (Box 92, Folder 14)
                - Hospital Council of Metropolitan Boston: minutes, 1953-54 (Box 93, Folder 1)
                - Health and hospital administration
                - Medical journals, 1951-54 (Box 93, Folder 2)
                - Pamphlets, 1951-54 (Box 93, Folder 3)
                - Articles, newsletters, and clippings, 1949-58, undated (Box 93, Folder 4)
                - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, 1950-55, undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
            - Suffrage and women's rights
              - Correspondence, 1914-65, undated (Box 94, Folder 1-3)
              - Speeches by Blanche Ames Ames: drafts, undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
              - Easton Equal Suffrage League: agenda, minutes, reports, financial records, and notes, 1914-15 (Box 94, Folder 5)
              - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association: minutes, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 6)
              - Signatures of citizens pledged to vote for woman suffrage, 1915 (Box 94, Folder 7)
              - Political cartoons by Blanche Ames Ames and others, 1914-15 (Box 94, Folder 8-10)
              - "Blanche Ames Ames and Woman Suffrage" by James J. Kenneally: pamphlet, and related article, 1993 (Box 94, Folder 11)
              - Clippings and brochures about suffrage, 1891-1960 (Box 94, Folder 12)
              - Photocopies of suffrage materials in the Schlesinger Library at Harvard University, 1892-1943, undated (Box 94, Folder 13)
              - Women's Centennial Congress
                - Correspondence and memoranda, 1940, undated (Box 94, Folder 14)
                - Clippings, programs, pamphlets, and reports, 1940-41, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
                - Commission on Ethical and Religious Values: speech by Blanche Ames Ames: draft and notes, 1940 (Box 95, Folder 2)
          - Subject files
            - Botanical: catalogs, brochures, order forms, and poems, 1947-57, undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
            - Business: articles, brochures, and pamphlets, 1933-66 (Box 95, Folder 4)
            - Civil defense: correspondence, articles, and clippings, 1954-55, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
            - Civil rights
              - Articles and notes, 1956-57, undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
              - Clippings, 1957-58, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
            - Conservation: articles, clippings, brochures, and pamphlets, 1955-66, undated (Box 95, Folder 8)
            - Desalinization: articles and clippings, 1945-65 (Box 95, Folder 9)
            - Harvard University: information about courses in economics, government and history, and the professors who taught them: correspondence and notes, 1951-57 (Box 95, Folder 10)
            - Politics: articles and clippings, 1838-1962, undated (Box 96, Folder 1)
            - Religion: brochures and essay, 1943-54, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
            - Science: articles and clippings, 1947-64, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
            - Uranium and radiation detection: articles, brochures, and pamphlets, 1957-61, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
            - Miscellaneous: brochures, magazines, and pamphlets, 1953-57, undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
        - Ames, Oakes (1874-1950)
          - Biographical materials
            - General, 1938-2004, undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
              [see also Pauline Ames Plimpton: Writings]
            - Account of an Oakes Ames illness by Blanche Ames Ames, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 7)
            - Obituaries, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 8)
            - Condolences, 1950-51 (Box 96, Folder 9)
            - Memorial service, 1950 (Box 96, Folder 10)
            - Will and related documents, 1943-50 (Box 96, Folder 11)
            - Oakes Ames Papers at Harvard University: correspondence, 1989-90 (Box 96, Folder 12)
            - Memorials
              - Bronze bust (Harvard Museum of Natural History): correspondence and photographs, 1985-92 (includes Pauline Ames Plimpton correspondence) (Box 96, Folder 13)
              - Other: correspondence and photographs, 1950-67 (Box 96, Folder 14-15)
          - Correspondence
            - Personal
              - Ames, Amyas (son), 1916-19, 1937 (Box 96, Folder 16)
              - Ames, Anna C. (mother), 1897-1912, 1944 (Box 96, Folder 17)
              - Ames, Blanche Ames (wife), 1898-1943 (Box 96, Folder 18-20)
              - Ames, Blanche Butler (mother-in-law), 1900 (Box 96, Folder 21)
              - Ames, Oliver (son), 1919, 1938 (Box 96, Folder 22)
              - Davis, Evelyn Ames (daughter), 1919, 1945 (Box 96, Folder 23)
              - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (daughter), 1918-50 (Box 97, Folder 1-5)
              - Plimpton, Francis T.P. and Pauline, 1946-48 (Box 97, Folder 6)
              - Plimpton, Francis T.P., 1936-44 (Box 97, Folder 7)
            - Financial and legal
              - Family
                - Amodeo, Anna Ray (niece), 1930 (Box 97, Folder 8)
                - Hall, Susan Evelyn Ames (sister), 1932-35, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
                - Nowell, Anna Lee Ames (sister), 1924-32, undated (Box 97, Folder 10)
                - Nowell, Ames (son of Anna Lee Ames Nowell), 1928-32 (Box 97, Folder 11)
                - Zaiss, Lilian A. C., (niece) 1933-36, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
              - Ames Shovel and Tool Company, 1899, 1924 (Box 97, Folder 13)
              - Old Colony Trust Co., 1924-32 (Box 97, Folder 14)
              - General, 1898-1950, undated (Box 97, Folder 15)
          - Writings
            - Diary excerpts: typescripts, 1901, 1930 (Box 97, Folder 16)
            - A Handbook of Conservation: essay about frontispiece engraving, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 17)
            - "Outlines of Economic Botany," Bussey Institution Lectures, undated (Box 97, Folder 18)
            - Untitled essay, undated (possibly by Oakes Ames) (Box 97, Folder 19)
        - Ames, Butler (1871-1954)
          [see also SERIES II. REAL ESTATE - Villa Balbianello and OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
          - Biographical sketches, obituaries, condolence letter, and account of his last hours by Blanche Ames Ames, 1954, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
          - "General Butler Ames: A Life Sketch" by Daniel Saul Hirschfield, 1963 (Box 98, Folder 2)
          - Clippings and miscellaneous forms, 1899-1955, undated (Box 98, Folder 3)
          - Power of attorney, 1919 (Box 98, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence about Butler Ames, 1953-65 (Box 98, Folder 5)
          - Financial materials
            - Bills and receipts, 1892-1901 (Box 98, Folder 6)
            - Cancelled checks, 1900-01 (Box 98, Folder 7-10)
          - West Point
            - Notes, tests, and poem, circa 1890-94 (Box 98, Folder 11)
            - Endorsements, musters, report cards, and leave of absence permissions, circa 1890-94 (Box 98, Folder 12)
            - Invitations and memorabilia, 1890-94 (Box 98, Folder 13)
            - Brochures, 1891-94 (Box 98, Folder 14)
          - Political career
            - Clippings, 1899-1900, undated (Box 98, Folder 15)
            - Campaign literature, 1900 (Box 98, Folder 16)
            - Notes and speeches, undated (Box 98, Folder 17)
            - Legislative documents, 1900, undated (Box 98, Folder 18)
          - Correspondence
            - Outgoing
              - Ames, Adelbert (father), 1894-1933, undated (Box 98, Folder 19)
              - Ames, Blanche Butler (mother), 1884-1936, undated (Box 98, Folder 20-21)
              - Ames, Blanche Ames (sister), 1888-1954, undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
              - "Sisters," 1896 (Box 99, Folder 2)
              - Ames, Fifille Willis (wife), 1931 (Box 99, Folder 3)
            - Incoming
              - Extended family, 1892-94 (Box 99, Folder 4)
              - Acquaintances, 1891-94, undated (Box 99, Folder 5-9)
              - General, 1892-1950 (Box 99, Folder 10-12)
          - Inventions
            - "Silver Slippers": shoe inserts, undated (Box 100, Folder 1)
            - Ames Electric Stove
              - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box 100, Folder 2)
              - Recipe and instructions, undated (Box 100, Folder 3)
            - Odorless Cooker
              - Instructions, plans, and photographs, undated (Box 100, Folder 4)
          - Royal Arcanum (club or society): membership application, certificates, and pamphlets, 1898-1900, undated (Box 100, Folder 5)
          - Subject file: Lower California Company, incident at Magdalena Bay in 1871: correspondence and copies of contemporary reports, 1912 (Box 100, Folder 6)
        - Ames, William Hadwen (1861-1918): correspondence and clippings re: his estate, 1923, 1987 (Box 100, Folder 7)
        - Ames, Winthrop and Lucy: correspondence, 1921-48, undated (Box 100, Folder 8)
          [see also Blanche Ames Ames: Art]
        - Borden, Sarah Ames (1874-1931)
          - Correspondence
            - Ames, Adelbert (father), 1893-94, undated (Box 100, Folder 9)
            - Ames, Blanche Butler (mother), 1893-97, undated (Box 100, Folder 10)
            - Ames, Adelbert Jr. (brother), 1891 (Box 100, Folder 11)
            - Ames, Blanche Ames (sister), 1893-1930, undated (Box 100, Folder 12-13)
            - Ames, Butler (brother), 1889-94 (Box 100, Folder 14)
            - Stevens, Edith Ames (sister), undated (Box 100, Folder 15)
        - Borden, Spencer (1872-1937): correspondence, 1902-31 (Box 100, Folder 16)
        - Davis, Hildreth: correspondence, 1950s, 1960s (Box 101, Folder 1)
        - Hall, Susan Evelyn Ames: letters to "Will," undated (Box 101, Folder 2)
        - Hall, Frederick F.
          - Letters to Blanche Ames Ames, 1935-41, undated (Box 101, Folder 3)
          - Condolences re: death of Susan Evelyn Ames Hall, 1940-41, undated (Box 101, Folder 4)
        - Marshall, Jessie Ames (1882-1967)
          - Miscellaneous, 1940, 1967 (Box 101, Folder 4A)
          - Correspondence
            - Family
              - Ames, Adelbert (father), 1900, undated (Box 101, Folder 5)
              - Ames, Blanche Butler (mother), 1909-39 (Box 101, Folder 6)
              - Ames, Blanche Ames (sister), 1909-39 (Box 101, Folder 7-8)
              - Stevens, Edith Ames (sister), 1896-1949, undated (Box 101, Folder 9)
            - Beekman, Dean, undated (Box 101, Folder 10)
        - Marshall, Andrew M. (1879-1965): obituary, and correspondence, 1965, undated (Box 101, Folder 11)
        - Stevens, Edith Ames (1873-1958)
          - Correspondence
            - Outgoing
              - Ames, Adelbert (father), 1884-96 (Box 101, Folder 12)
              - Ames, Blanche Butler (mother), 1892-1934 (Box 101, Folder 13)
              - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1893-1956, undated (Box 101, Folder 14-15)
              - Ames, Butler (brother), 1892-96 (Box 102, Folder 1)
              - Borden, Sarah Ames (sister), 1893-1916, undated (Box 102, Folder 2)
              - Marshall, Jessie Ames (sister), 1896-1935 (Box 102, Folder 3)
            - Incoming from various individuals, 1943-63 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        - Stevens, C. Brooks (1864-1949): correspondence, 1942-44 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - GENERATION V
        - Ames, Adelbert III (b. 1921) and Judith Derby Ames (1923-1973): correspondence, 1920s-1960s (Box 102, Folder 6)
        - Ames, Amyas (1906-2000)
          - Biographical materials
            - Academic records and related correspondence, 1916-32 (Box 102, Folder 7)
            - Clippings, marriage announcement, and obituary, 1918-2000, undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
          - Correspondence
            - Blanche Ames Ames and Oakes Ames (parents), circa 1910-69, undated (Box 102, Folder 9-11)
            - Ames, Evelyn (sister), 1924 (Box 102, Folder 12)
            - Ames, Evelyn Ingeborg Perkins (wife), 1940s (Box 102, Folder 13)
            - Ames, Oliver (brother), 1924, 1950 (Box 102, Folder 14)
            - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (sister), 1924-94, undated (Box 102, Folder 15)
            - Other, 1980-94 (Box 102, Folder 16)
          - Writings, 1974-90, undated (Box 102, Folder 17)
        - Ames, Evelyn Ingeborg Perkins (1908-1990)
          - Clipping, funeral program, eulogies, and obituary, 1990, undated (Box 102, Folder 18)
          - Correspondence, 1920s-1960s (Box 102, Folder 19)
        - Ames, John ("Jack"): correspondence, 1952-54 (Box 102, Folder 20)
        - Ames, Oliver (1903-1971)
          - Obituary, and academic records and related correspondence, 1914-71, undated (Box 102, Folder 21)
          - Correspondence (Box 102)
            - Ames, Blanche Ames (mother), 1915-64 (Box 102, Folder 22)
            - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (sister), 1942-64, undated (Box 102, Folder 23)
            - Others, 1928, 1954 (Box 102, Folder 24)
        - Ames, Ellen Moseley (b. 1919): correspondence, 1940s-1960s (Box 102, Folder 25)
        - Borden, Richard (b. 1920) and Elizabeth McGinley Borden (b. 1913): correspondence, 1942-63 (Box 102, Folder 26)
        - Bruner, Blanche Marshall (b. 1915): correspondence, 1964-67, undated (Box 102, Folder 27)
        - Colt, Joan Borden (1907-1995): correspondence and obituary, 1930s-66, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 28)
        - Davis, Evelyn Ames (1910-1993)
          - Biographical materials
            - Condolences and tributes, 1993 (Box 103, Folder 1)
            - Academic records, clippings, and correspondence 1917-90 (Box 103, Folder 2)
          - Poems, undated (Box 3)
          - Correspondence
            - Ames, Amyas (brother), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
            - Ames, Blanche Ames and Oakes Ames (parents), circa 1920-1960s, undated (Box 3, Folder 5-10)
            - Davis, Blanche (daughter), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
            - Plimpton, Oakes (nephew), 1974 (Box 103A, Folder 1)
            - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (sister), 1920-86, undated (Box 103A, Folder 2-6)
            - Stevens, Edith Ames (aunt), 1943 (Box 103A, Folder 7)
            - Acquaintances, 1956, 1986, undated (Box 103A, Folder 8)
      - Davis, John Paschall (1908-1977)
        - Eulogy, 1977 (Box 103A, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence, 1935-66 (Box 103A, Folder 10)
        - Sermons, 1965-66 (Box 103A, Folder 11)
      - Frenning, Blanche Borden (b. 1902): correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames (aunt), 1931-67, undated (Box 104, Folder 1)
        - Borden, Sarah A. and Spencer (parents), 1934 (Box 104, Folder 2)
        - Plimpton, Pauline Ames, 1920-28, undated (Box 104, Folder 3)
        - Financial, 1938 (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - Marshall, Andrew, Jr. (b.1912): correspondence, 1960s (Box 104, Folder 5)
      - Marshall, Malcolm (b. 1919): correspondence, 1942, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (1901-1995)
        - Biographical materials
          - General, 1964-85, undated (Box 104, Folder 7)
        - Education (Box 104)
          - Primary and secondary school records, 1911-16 (Box 104, Folder 7A)
          - Smith College (Box 104)
            - Essays and exams, 1918-22 (Box 104, Folder 8-10)
            - Exam questions, 1918-22 (Box 104, Folder 11)
            - Course notes, 1918-22 (Box 104)
              - Archaeology - History (English) (Box 104, Folder 12-23)
              - History (U.S.) - Mathematics (Box 105, Folder 1-3)
            - Report cards and commencement program, 1918-22 (Box 105, Folder 4)
          - Postgraduate essays and notes, 1923-25, undated (Box 105, Folder 5-7)
        - Passport, 1921 (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - Interview: transcript, 1987 (Box 9)
        - Biographical sketches, obituary, resumes, and clippings, 1956-95, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Account of childbirth experiences (for book by Patricia Bernstein), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Awards, 1985-96, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Fiftieth wedding anniversary party
          - Correspondence, Jun 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
          - Manual, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
          - Guest lists, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Other parties, 1974-86 (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Society of Mayflower Descendants: correspondence and forms, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 1)
        - Marriage and death certificates, drivers license, Social Security card, and obituaries, 1926, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 2)
        - Wills, Power of Attorney, health care proxy, and related correspondence, 1956-93 (Box 106, Folder 3)
        - Condolences, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 4)
        - Funeral
          - Program, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 5)
          - Guest books, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 5A)
        - Appointment books, 1989-95 (Box 106, Folder 6)
        - Photographs of furniture and related correspondence, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 7)
        - Travel
          - Central America
            - Diary, 1923 (Box 106, Folder 8)
            - Typescript of 1923 diary, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 9)
            - Photograph album, 1923 (Box 106, Folder 10)
          - China: itinerary, correspondence, reminiscence, memorabilia, and notes, 1976 (Box 107, Folder 1)
          - Paris, France
            - Correspondence, 1929-31 (Box 107, Folder 2)
            - Compilation of original correspondence: typescripts, 1980 (Box 107, Folder 3)
          - Mediterranean cruise: correspondence, itinerary, and invoices, 1988, undated (Box 107, Folder 4)
          - Other: correspondence, itineraries, and passenger list, 1956-89, undated (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - Financial and legal materials
        - Blanche Ames Ames Trust: correspondence and legal documents, 1970-75 (Box 107, Folder 6)
        - William Hadwen Ames Trust: correspondence, legal documents, and statements of account, 1982-86 (Box 107, Folder 7)
        - Paul Butler Trust
          - Correspondence and statements of account, 1969-90 (Box 107, Folder 8)
          - Family Policy Group: correspondence, minutes, reports, and miscellaneous, 1944-68 (Box 107, Folder 9-10)
        - Evelyn Ames Hall Trust: correspondence and legal documents, 1948 (Box 107, Folder 11)
        - Union Land and Grazing Company: correspondence and reports, 1983-94 (Box 107, Folder 12)
        - Financial statements and related correspondence, 1939-94 (Box 107, Folder 13-14)
        - Gifts, bequests, and donations
          - Family
            - Trusts for children of Pauline Ames Plimpton and Francis T. P. Plimpton, 1976, 1981 (Box 107, Folder 15)
            - Stocks and securities, 1976 (Box 108, Folder 1)
          - Charitable donations: correspondence and lists, 1986-95, undated (Box 108, Folder 2)
        - Consignment of literary manuscripts: correspondence, contracts, and statements of account, 1975-86 (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Artwork: inventories and notes, 1968-91, undated (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - Real estate
        - Sweet Hollow Farm (Huntington, NY)
          - Ownership and upkeep: correspondence and memoranda, 1941-94 (Box 108, Folder 5)
          - Landscaping: correspondence and memoranda, 1992 (Box 108, Folder 6)
          - Proposal to subdivide property: correspondence, memoranda, legal documents, and maps, 1985-90, undated (Box 108, Folder 7)
          - Sale of property to Nature Conservancy: correspondence, memoranda, contracts, and legal documents, 1989-93 (Box 108, Folder 8)
          - Maps of Huntington, NY and environs, undated (Box 108, Folder 9)
        - Apartment (New York, NY)
          - Appraisal, 1993 (Box 108, Folder 10)
          - Correspondence and financial information, 1968, 1992 (Box 108, Folder 11)
          - Interior design
            - Estimates, invoices, and notes, 1966-76, undated (Box 108, Folder 12)
            - Esther Willcox (interior designer): invoices, 1967-69 (Box 108, Folder 13)
            - Furniture ideas: pages from magazines, brochures, and notes, 1968, undated (Box 108, Folder 14)
            - Carpet, fabric, paint and wallpaper samples, circa 1968-69 (Box 108)
              - Big room (Box 108, Folder 15)
              - Guest room (Box 108, Folder 16)
              - Library (Box 108, Folder 17-18)
              - Living room (Box 109, Folder 1)
              - Master bedroom (Box 109, Folder 2)
              - Pantry hall (Box 109, Folder 3)
              - Rear hall (Box 109, Folder 4)
              - Unidentified rooms (Box 109, Folder 5-6)
            - Fireplace and bookcase designs: estimates, plans, drawings, and photographs, 1968 (Box 109, Folder 7)
        - Measurements for rooms in various Plimpton residences, undated (Box 109, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence
        - Outgoing
          - Ames, Amyas (brother), undated (Box 109, Folder 9)
          - Ames, Blanche Ames and Oakes Ames (parents)
            - Circa 1910-Mar 1918 (Box 109, Folder 10)
            - While attending Smith College, Oct 1918-1922, undated (Box 109, Folder 11-15)
            - 1928-1932 (Box 109, Folder 16-19)
            - 1933-59, undated 1950s (Box 110, Folder 1-13)
            - 1960-68, undated (Box 110A, Folder 1-3)
          - Ames, Ellen Moseley (sister-in-law), 1960 (Box 110A, Folder 4)
          - Davis, Evelyn Ames (sister), 1918-69, undated (Box 110A, Folder 5-10)
          - Plimpton, Francis T.P. (husband)
            - 1925-33 (Box 110A, Folder 11-14)
            - 1934-65, undated (Box 111, Folder 1-4)
          - Miscellaneous, 1941-94, undated (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - Incoming
          - Hall, Elton, 1972 (Box 111, Folder 6)
          - Kirshner, Ralph, 1994 (Box 111, Folder 7)
          - Plimpton, Fanny (Ann) Hastings, 1927-29, 1940s (Box 111, Folder 8)
          - Plimpton, George Arthur, 1926, 1929 (Box 111, Folder 9)
          - Plimpton, Ruth (sister-in-law), 1958-59, undated (Box 111, Folder 10)
          - Schultes, Richard Evans, 1969-85, undated (Box 111, Folder 11)
            [see also Ames, Blanche Ames - Correspondence]
          - Others, 1918-95, undated (Box 111, Folder 12-18)
      - Activities
        - Academic institutions
          - Amherst College: correspondence and pamphlet, 1936, 1979-94 (Box 112, Folder 1)
          - Columbia University: correspondence and pamphlet, 1934, 1984-94, undated (Box 112, Folder 2)
          - Harvard University: preservation of the glass flowers, 1975-81 (Box 112, Folder 3-4)
          - Smith College
            - General, 1966-81 (Box 112, Folder 5)
            - Alumnae and fundraising: correspondence and financial information, 1970-95, undated (Box 112, Folder 6-8)
            - Libraries, Smith College Archives, and Sophia Smith Collection: correspondence
              - 1965-83 (Box 112, Folder 9-10)
              - 1984-94, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
            - Smith College Museum of Art: Orchids and Artists exhibit: correspondence, speech, and catalog, 1991 (Box 113, Folder 2)
          - University of Texas at Austin: Lundell Library, 1968-85, undated (Box 113, Folder 3-4)
          - Libraries
            - Folger Shakespeare Library: correspondence and contracts, 1981-91 (Box 113, Folder 5)
            - Schlesinger Library, 1966-83, undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
          - Other educational institutions: correspondence, 1988-95, undated (Box 113, Folder 7)
        - Cultural and philanthropic organizations
          - American Red Cross: correspondence, 1986-87 (Box 113, Folder 8)
          - Foreign Visitors Committee: correspondence and memoranda, 1990-92 (Box 113, Folder 9)
          - Institute of World Affairs: correspondence, agendas, and reports, 1967-89, undated (Box 113, Folder 10)